嘿  查莉  这是一个激动人心的时刻
Hey, Charlie. So, exciting times for the Duncan family.
明天  你就三岁了
Tomorrow, you turn three!
耶
Yay!
如果这还不够兴奋  一周前  新宝宝的预产期到了
And if that wasn't exciting enough, one week ago, the new baby was due.
现在让我们来看看小宝宝在干什么
Let's see how that baby's doing now.
你给我出来
I want you out!
邓肯五号迟迟不来
Duncan kid number five is late.
邓肯二号把我惹毛了
And Duncan kid number two is getting on my nerves.
继续聊
Moving on.
话说回来  我希望是个女孩
Anyway, I'm hoping for a baby girl.
我希望是男孩
I'm hoping for a baby boy.
是啊
Yeah.
我也是
Me too.
我想要个弟弟逗一逗
I want a younger brother to pick on.
我已经逗烦那边的老兄了
I'm tired of picking on my older brother.
噢  男孩女孩我都不介意
Oh, boy or girl doesn't matter to me.
老妈喜欢啥  我就喜欢啥
Whatever Mom wants, I want.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
下不为例  亲爱的
Never again, honey.
又拍到不该拍的画面了
Once again I've kept the camera on just a smidge too long.
同志们  事情太多了
Guys, this is all just too much.
新生儿要降临了  查莉明天就要过生日了
The new baby's about to come, and Charlie's birthday tomorrow.
只要不发生在同一天
Just so long as they don't happen on the same day.
-什么意思  -想一想
-What do you mean? -Well, think about it.
如果查莉要和新生儿共同分享生日的喜悦
Wouldn't it be kind of sad if Charlie had to
岂不是很悲剧
share her birthday with the new baby?
我告诉你什么最悲剧
I'll tell you what's sad.
我们的吐司条没了
We're out of French Toast sticks.
泰迪  新生儿该什么时候来  就什么时候来
Teddy, honey, the baby's gonna come when the baby wants to come.
但是如果真是明天就来
But if it does happen to be tomorrow,
我需要大家都帮忙弄一下查莉的生日
I need everyone to help out with Charlie's birthday.
老妈  我会像平常一样帮你排忧解难的
Mom, I'm willing to help out by doing what I always do.
你以前什么都没做过
You don't ever do anything.
这才是我最拿手的
And nobody does it better.
我只想说  如果咱们家里
All I'm saying is if somebody goes to the trouble
没吐司条了  至少我们应该去买点吧
of inventing French Toast sticks, the least we could do is buy their product.
老鲍  你把我交代过你的事情办完了吗
Bob, honey, you took care of those things I asked you to handle, right?
我
I..
肯定办完了
Certainly did.
为什么在“我”和“肯定”之间停顿了一下
Why was there a pause between "I" and "certainly"?
没停顿啊
No pause.
就是我正常说话
Just my normal speaking..
的语速啊
Talk voice pattern.
那么  你买了婴儿汽车座椅
So, you bought the baby's new car seat,
和查莉的生日礼物洋娃娃
and the doll Charlie wants for her birthday?
亲啊  我全办妥了
Honey. I did it all.
成了吧  完满完成任务
Okay? Mission accomplished.
我
I..
相信你
Believe you.
呃  盖比
Uh, Gabe?
-怎么了  -听着  这里是  呃
-Yeah? -Listen, here is, uh..
这是五十块钱
Here's 50 bucks.
我需要你去趟商场
I need you to go down to the mall.
给查莉买个洋娃娃回来
I need you to get that doll for Charlie.
爸啊  你怎么不去
Dad, why can't you do it?
因为我要去买婴儿汽车座椅
Because I gotta buy a car seat.
你知道有些女孩长大后
You know how some little girls grow up
都会挑一个和她们爸爸很像的男人做老公
and pick a husband who's just like their Daddy?
我是不会的
I'm gonna go a different way.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录 www.Deefun.com
生活搞得一团糟
<i>Today's all burnt toast </i>
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
<i>Running late, and dad jokes</i>
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
<i>Has anybody seen my left shoe</i>
■
翻译： Johnny-Z
我闭上眼  咬口早餐
<i>I close my eyes, take a bite</i>
跳上车子  放声大笑
<i>Grab a ride, laugh out loud</i>
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
<i>There it is up on the roof</i>
■
后期： Johnny-Z  liloelva
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
<i>I've been there, I've survived</i>
所以听取我的建议
<i>So just take my advice</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
世界有很多疯狂无奈
<i>Things are crazy</i>
可是我知道你会有美好将来
<i>But I know your future's bright</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
不要怀疑
<i>There's no maybe</i>
一切终会如你所愿
<i>Everything turns out all right</i>
生活有悲有喜
<i>Your life is up and down</i>
但是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
<i>But trust me it comes back around</i>
你会喜欢将来的你
<i>You're gonna love</i> <i>who you turn out to be</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby.</i>
查莉成长日记  第三季第七集
Good Luck Charlie  S03E07  Special Delivery
嘿  亲爱的
Hey, honey?
嘿  过来
Hey, come on.
我给你看点儿东西
There's something I want to show you.
亲爱的  过来啊
Honey, come on.
我正在全速前进
I'm moving as fast as I can.
大腹便便向前冲
Wide load coming through.
看
Look.
看啊
新的儿童座椅
New car seat is in.
-不错  -是啊
-Good. -Yeah.
三天前买回来的  已经不重要了
Bought it three days ago. Well, whatever.
这里面看起来有点儿挤
Looks a little crowded in here.
怎么会呢  亲爱的  我们坐前排  谁管后面挤不挤
Well, honey, we're gonna be up front. Who cares what happens in the back?
老鲍  我觉着空间不够大
Bob, I don't think there's enough room.
空间足够大啊
Sure there is.
不是的  老鲍  五个孩子啊  我觉着该买辆新车了
No, Bob, with five kids, I think we might need a new car.
别急
Slow down.
不  不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
有足够的空间给每一个人
Enough room in here for everybody.
你看  查莉坐这  小宝宝坐那
Look, Charlie sits here, new baby over there,
再来个孩子坐后面  另一个坐那边
one kid back there, the other over there.
看  问题解决了
Done. Problem solved.
你少算了一个
You forgot a kid.
哪个
Which one?
不知道
I don't know.
反正有五个孩子
But I know there are five.
没问题的
This can work.
我给你演示下  崽子们
Let me show you.. Kids!
好了  看吧
There, see?
小事一桩
Piece of cake.
后面的同志怎么样啊
How's everybody doing back there?
PJ用肋骨硌我
PJ keeps poking me with his rib.
我需要呼吸的
It's called breathing.
亲爱的  盖比连安全带都没有
Honey, Gabe doesn't have a seat belt.
甚至是座椅
Or a seat.
他没事的
He'll be fine.
嘿  查莉
Hey, Charlie?
你还舒服吗
Are you comfortable?
不
No.
-老鲍  -啥事
-Bob? -Yes?
-新车  -新车
-New car? -New car.
好了
Okay.
可以涂了
Here we go.
噢
Oh.
嘿  妈  噢
Hey, Mom? Oh..
练什么功呢
What are you doing?
涂指甲油呢
Painting my toenails.
尽管我看不见脚趾甲  那也要让它漂漂亮亮的
Just because I can't see them doesn't mean they shouldn't look good.
噢  既然这样  不如直接剪了它
Oh. Well in that case, you might want to consider clipping them.
你到底有啥事
Can I help you?
这样的  我是来帮助你的
Well, I am actually here to help you.
老妈  我知道你最近情绪暴躁
So, Mom, I know that you've been very anxious
因为小宝宝的事情  所以我上网
to get this baby out, so I went online
查了查如何用自然的方法引产
and I looked up some natural ways to induce labor.
呜  什么方法
Ooh, like what?
呃  有很多方法  首先第一个就是
Well, uh, there's a bunch of techniques, but the first one includes..
吥
Boo!
搞什么
What was that?
尝试把小宝宝吓出来
I was trying to scare the baby out.
看来  没起作用啊
Well, it didn't work.
好吧
Okay.
好了  肯定还有其他什么办法的  比如
Fine, well, there's always some other stuff we can try, like..
吥
Boo!
别闹了
Stop that.
好了  你也知道  这个是孩子
Okay, you know, it's a baby.
不是打嗝
It's not the hiccups.
那么  你今天打算干什么
So, what do you want to do today?
今儿个天不错
Well, it's a beautiful day.
阳光啊  鸟鸣啊
Sun shining, the birds are chirping..
所以  地下室打游戏去
So, video games in the basement?
老兄  刚才那番很浪漫的话  真是把我吓坏了
Dude, you had me scared there for a minute with all the outdoor talk.
好了  走吧
All right, let's go.
等等
Wait.
我答应过我老爸  要去商店给查莉买娃娃
I promised my Dad I'd go to the store and buy Charlie a stupid doll.
我还跟我老妈说我去图书馆了呢
And I told my Mom I was at the library.
那又怎样
So what?
算了  杰克  我真的要去商店买娃娃
No, Jake, I really have to go do this.
好吧  又没人拦着你
So, who's stopping you?
我坐在这里等你
I'll wait right here.
算了  你知道我不能把你单独留在家里
Yeah, you know I'm not allowed to leave you in this house alone.
走吧
Come on.
天啊  你真是一朝被蛇咬  十年怕井绳啊
Man, you take one bubble bath, you get labeled.
这都是啥
What's all this?
我弄了几个健身球
I got us some yoga balls.
通过弹跳来帮助你引产
Another way to induce labor is through bouncing.
好吧  试试吧
All right, I'll try anything.
开始吧  查莉
Hit it, Charlie.
有感觉了吗
Feel anything?
感觉好傻
I feel silly.
看着就傻
You look silly.
噢
Oh.
泰迪  这没用的
Teddy, this isn't going to work.
再来
Do it again.
老兄  我不能被人看见我在买娃娃
Dude, I can't be seen doll shopping.
你以后让我怎么在道上混
I'll lose my street cred.
是吗  我猜你在卖内衣那里傻笑的时候  就没法在道上混了
Yeah, I think you lost that when you started giggling in the bra Department.
赶紧买完就撤吧
Let's just buy this thing and get out of here.
凯蒂洋娃娃
Kuddle Me Katie?
真弱智
That's stupid.
咕咕
Goo-goo.
说了句咕咕
It said goo-goo.
哇  看看这新产品
Whoa, look what they just released.
扎提亚斯的攻击
Attack of the Zartians.
噢  没错  我听说过这个游戏
Oh, right. I heard about this game.
扎提亚斯和火星人被僵尸咬了
Zartians are martians that were bitten by zombies.
呦  真恶心
Ewe. That's disgusting.
他们身上的是什么啊  血还是呕吐物
What are they covered in, blood or puke?
希望都有
Hopefully both.
买了吧
Let's get it.
五十块钱呢  我没有五十块钱了
It's 50 bucks. I don't have 50 bucks.
有的  你有
Yeah, you do.
等一下
Wait a minute.
-你是  你是想说  -正是我想说的
-Are you.. Are you saying.. -That's exactly what I'm saying.
你用买娃娃的钱  来买游戏
You're gonna buy this game with the doll money.
没错
Yeah.
-那接下来怎么办  -玩之
-And then what? -We play it.
-玩完之后呢  -复玩之
-After we play it? -We play it again.
那  那查莉的娃娃怎么办
Well, what about Charlie's doll?
我答应过我爸了
I promised my Dad.
老兄  我们现在是青少年了  应该叛逆点儿
Dude, we're teenagers now. We're supposed to be rebels.
你老妈还给你买内衣呢
Your Mom still picks out your underwear.
有时候我反着穿
And sometimes I wear it backwards.
故意的
On purpose.
知道吗  我要买这游戏
You know what? I'm gonna buy this game,
就是为了能停止讨论你的内衣的问题
but just so we can stop talking about your underwear.
嘿  老妈
Hey, Mom.
干啥呢
How you doing?
我疲倦  臃肿  暴躁  到达了人生的谷底
I am tired, bloated, cranky, I have never been more miserable in my life.
很不错
That's nice.
嘿
Hey..
我刚才检查了下冰箱里的速冻食品
I just did a quick freezer check..
还是没有看见吐司条
Still not seeing the French Toast sticks.
我给你买了啊
I bought you some.
是啊  但你买的是土司块
Yeah, you bought French Toast squares.
如果你想要条的  就把块的从中间一切为二啊
Well, if you want sticks, then just take the squares and cut them in half.
一切为二
Cut them in half?
这样一来  乐趣也一切为二了
But then you cut the fun in half.
宝贝  你会整明白的
Honey, you'll figure it out.
我觉着我可以把两半儿的吐司条
I guess I could take the cut squares..
用糖浆把它们纵向粘起来
And glue them together lengthwise with syrup..
也许果酱是个更好的选择
Or would jam make a better adhesive?
我还是睡一觉吧
I'd better nap on it.
那是你大哥  PJ
That's your big brother, PJ.
他除了不是很聪明
He's not the smartest..
没别的了
That's it.
嘿  老妈  你饿了吗
Hey, Mom. You hungry?
噢  不饿
Oh, no.
宝贝  我吃不下了
Honey, I couldn't eat anything.
太饱了  我只是  我只是
I'm so big, I just.. I just..
有什么吃的
What you got?
印度菜馆的咖喱胡椒酱
Vindaloo Pepper Curry from the new Indian place.
因为我刚学到可以用辛辣食物来协助引产
Because I read that another way to induce labor is with spicy food.
真的很辛辣吗
Is it really that spicy?
绝对  因为辣  他们逼我签下了生死状
Yeah, so spicy, they made me sign a waiver.
并出席宣讲会
And attend a brief seminar.
试试呗
Let's try it.
老爸
Dad!
我刚放这里的  也就一分钟
I set that down, like, one minute ago.
这东西太给力了
Stuff's got some kick to it.
你还有啥招
What else you got?
那么  跳肚皮舞有什么帮助吗
So, uh, how is belly dancing supposed to help?
他们说跳这个可以锻炼到你的腹内
Well, they say that it's good to exercise your core, and..
说实话  现在
Let's face it, right now..
你腹内都满了
You're all core.
噢
Oh..
看看啊  有点儿意思
Check it out, this is fun.
吃惊啊  吃惊
And surprise, surprise.
我跳得真好
I'm good at it.
有感觉了吗  妈
Feel anything, Mom?
感觉我的肚皮舞跳得比你好一百倍
Feel like I'm kicking your butt at belly dancing.
-噢  没有  你瞎说  -噢  我没瞎说
-Oh, no, you're not. -Oh, yes, I am.
-来啊  -瞧好吧
-Bring it. -Consider it brung.
-噢  -耶
-Oh! -Yeah!
耶  你出局了
Yeah, you just got served.
被我虐了  秒杀了
In a bowl, with a spoon.
没想到跳肚皮舞能有这么多垃圾话
Didn't realize belly dancing had so much trash talk.
天啊  真让人失望
Man, this is frustrating.
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I know.
他们真应该弄个大一点儿的键盘
They really need to make bigger keyboards
给那些手指又肥又大的人用
for people with big, sausage-y fingers.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你又在说什么
我在琢磨应该买哪辆车
I'm trying to figure out what kind of car to buy.
问题是  有太多东西需要选择了
Problem is, you got too many choices.
你就要做出选择
And then you gotta figure out..
里程数啊
Mileage and..
颜色啊  安全度啊  可靠性啊
Color, safety, reliability..
知道吗  这就是天方夜谭
You know what? This is impossible.
这辆怎么样
Well, what about this one?
你看  给那家人带来了多少快乐
I mean, look how happy it's making that family.
噢  他们要周游全国
Oh, and they're going across the country.
拉什莫尔山
Mount Rushmore.
科罗拉多大峡谷
The Grand Canyon..
外婆家
Grandma's house.
PJ
PJ.
别逗了  这只是个广告  你
Come on, it's just a commercial, you..
嘿  他们给她带了只小狗
Hey, they brought her a puppy.
噢  这正是她想要的
Oh, it's just what she wanted.
我们要拥有这辆车
We have to get that car.
能给我们带来快乐
If we want to be happy.
好了  沙拉怎么帮我生孩子
Okay, how is a salad going to help me go into labor?
不是沙拉  是沙拉酱
Not the salad, the dressing.
看  这家店因此而闻名
See, this place is famous for it.
他们有种独家秘密食材  能马上让孩子出来
They have this special secret ingredient that just pops a kid right out.
值得一试
It's worth a shot.
另外  我已经十五分钟没有进食了
Besides, I haven't eaten in like, 15 minutes.
嗨  需要帮助吗
Hi. Can I help you?
好的  两位  谢谢
Yes. A table for two, please.
好的  能告诉我你的名字吗  我们已经排到三小时以外了
Sure, can I get your name? We have about a three-hour wait.
三个小时
Three hours?
但是我们现在就需要入座
But we need a table right away.
是的  我怀孕了
Yes, I'm pregnant.
属于特殊情况
It's kind of a special circumstance.
噢  这样的话  你可以在我们的特殊区域等候
Oh, well, in that case, you can wait in our special section.
太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
不敢相信他们让咱们站在这里等
I can't believe they're making us stand here like this.
我都过预产期七天了
I'm seven days overdue.
七天吗
Seven days?
试试九天的什么感觉
Try nine days on for size.
回首七天的日子  简直就是天堂
I'm looking back at seven days like it was a party.
噢  是吗
Oh, yeah?
我肚子里的气都能飞到伦敦
I have enough gas to fly to London.
试试中国
Try China.
那桌吃完了吗
How's that table coming?
-好了  -等不急要玩这游戏了
-All right. -I can't wait to play this game.
是啊  从你用牙咬开包装盒就可以看出来了
Yeah, I was getting that from the way you opened the box with your teeth.
我都是这么开东西
That's how I open everything.
要不然我戴牙套干吗
Why do you think I need braces?
现在  如果我爸下楼来
Now, if my Dad comes down.
问我娃娃在哪呢  我该怎么告诉他
And asks where the doll is, what am I gonna tell him?
有了  想到了
Okay, I got it.
我就告诉他  在去往商店的途中  我被一帮人给揍了
I'll tell him that.. On the way to the toy store, I got beat up by a gang.
而且
And..
他们偷走了钱  我很幸运的保住了性命
They stole the money and I'm lucky to be alive.
老兄  面对的是你老爸
Dude, it's your Dad we're talking about.
干嘛这么费力编故事
Why are you working so hard on a story?
你还别说
You know what?
你说对了
You're right.
我干嘛为查莉的破娃娃而费心呢
Why am I worried about Charlie's stupid doll anyway?
好了  给
All right, here.
呃噢  什么意思
Uh-oh. What's that?
“警告”
"Warning."
“含有暴力画面”
"Contains scenes of graphic violence."
“建议在家长的陪伴下进行游戏”
"Parental supervision strongly advised."
爽
Yes!
听着  我的羊水太多了  走路都往外溅
Well, I retain so much water, I slosh when I walk.
我睡觉的时候都往外溅
I slosh when I sleep.
噢  睡觉的时候吗
Oh, you sleep?
噢   妈
Oh, Mom.
我刚想到一个主意
I just thought of a great idea.
我们为啥不外带沙拉
Why don't we get the salads to go?
你以为我们没想过吗
Don't you think we thought of that?
他们没有外卖服务
They don't do takeout here.
希望你的下一个孩子比这个聪明点儿
Sure hope your next kid is smarter than this one.
嘿
Hey.
除了我没人能损我的孩子
Nobody insults my kids but me.
你不服啊
You want a piece of me?
-你不服啊  -好了  女士们  消消气
-You want a piece of me? -Okay! Ladies, let's break it up.
咱们走吧  好不  我在这里忍不了三个小时
Let's just go, okay? I can't do this for three hours.
什么  不成  老妈  我们要坚持下
What? No, Mom. We have to stick it out.
孩子必须要今天生
The baby has to be born today.
因为明天是查莉的生日
Tomorrow's Charlie's birthday.
宝贝  我知道  但是我们在这里已经别无选择了
Honey, I know that. But we're out of options here.
不一定哦
Or are we?
看那儿
Look over there.
那一定是秘制沙拉酱
That must be the salad dressing.
好了  你去分散大家的注意力  我去搞沙拉酱
Okay, so you create a distraction for everyone, and I'll go get it.
我们要去偷沙拉酱吗
We're going to steal salad dressing?
你出师了
The student becomes the master.
噢  天啊
Oh my!
噢  天啊  要生了
Oh my! It's happening.
噢  老娘要生孩子了
Oh, Mama's having a baby child!
好了  先冷静下来
Okay, just stay calm.
会没事的
Everything's gonna be okay.
-好的  -呼吸
-Okay. -Just breathe.
噢  不好意思
Oh, you know what?
虚惊一场
False alarm.
抱歉
Sorry.
大家都忙去吧  我这里没事了
Everybody go back to your salads, nothing more to see here.
噢
Oh.
快撤吧
Let's get out of here.
嘿  拦住他们  他们偷走了沙拉酱
Hey! Stop them, they've got the dressing.
跑啊
Run for it!
噢  好吧
Oh. Okay.
嘿  大家放松下
Hey, everybody relax.
是啊  没必要这样  好吗  我们有足够的沙拉酱给大家
Yeah, no need to get crazy, okay, there's plenty of dressing for everyone.
我怀的是双胞胎
I am having twins.
我要双份
I want double.
噢  是吗  给我看看超声波证明下
Oh, yeah? I'm gonna need to see an ultrasound.
嘿  嘿  退后
Hey, hey! Back off.
再走一步  我就摔了
One more step and the dressing gets it.
没错
That's right.
你听到了
You heard her.
现在大家都闪开一条道
Now everyone waddle away real nice-like.
你先闪  双黄蛋
You first, twinsie.
那么  鲍伯
So, Bob.
你是喜欢这辆小夜曲的哪些呢
What got you interested in the Serenade?
这个嘛  里程数啊  安全度啊  可靠性啊
Well, the mileage, safety, reliability..
是因为小狗吗
Was it the puppy?
是的
Yeah.
那么  你觉着如何
So, what do you think?
操控性能很好  是吧
Rides pretty smooth, doesn't it?
是啊  还成吧
Yeah, it's.. It's okay, I guess.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
我感觉坐在了筋斗云上
I feel like I'm floating on a cloud.
能加热的筋斗云
A cloud with seat warmers.
这就是为什么我下面暖暖的
So that's why I'm so toasty down there.
看来你的公子挺喜欢这辆车啊
Sounds like your boy likes the car.
六个杯托
Six cup holders?!
小夜曲  小夜曲
Serenade! Serenade!
小夜曲
Serenade!
你觉着呢  鲍伯
What do you say, Bob?
准备好进去办点儿手续吗
You want to go inside and we'll crunch some numbers?
呃  能让我俩商量商量吗  斯图
Um.. Could you give us a minute, Stu?
当然可以  我在展厅等你
Sure thing. I'll be in the showroom.
PJ
PJ!
你在干什么  你在搞砸这笔交易
What are you doing? You're blowing the whole deal!
你什么意思
What do you mean?
如果斯图认为我们喜欢这辆车  他肯定会把价位提高
If Stu thinks we like the car, we're gonna have to pay more for it.
我们要让他认为咱们不喜欢这辆车
We gotta make him think we don't want the car.
那我们有可能不买这辆车吗
So there's a chance we won't buy it?
开什么玩笑  我太喜欢这辆车了
Are you kidding me? I love this thing!
小夜曲  小夜曲  小夜曲
Serenade! Serenade! Serenade!
真没想到孕妇能这么凶残
Never knew pregnant women could be so vicious.
吓死老娘了
It was horrifying.
有个女的咬掉了我的几个纽扣
That one gal chewed off a couple of my buttons.
不如咱们下楼继续练健身球吧
Why don't we go downstairs again and try bouncing..
噢  不  不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
宝贝  我们够了
Sweetie, we are done.
好了  我们试过了每种方法
Okay, we've tried everything.
这个小宝宝的生辰八字由天注定
This baby is gonna come when it wants to.
大概是吧
I guess you're right.
如果真的在查莉生日的时候出生
And if it is born on Charlie's birthday,
也许并非坏事
maybe that wouldn't be such a bad thing.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我也不清楚
Well, I don't know, with..
五个孩子  也许在生日的时候  折磨不会加剧
Five kids, maybe it wouldn't hurt to double up on birthdays.
明白吗
You know..
更少的派对  更少的礼物  更少的头疼
Less parties, less presents, less headaches..
嘿
Hey.
也许我可以告诉查莉和小宝宝他们生在圣诞节
Maybe I can tell Charlie and the baby they were born on December 25.
所以  看我眼色行事
So, follow my lead.
表现出淡定
Play it cool.
噢  不管发生什么  都不要太猴急
Oh, and whatever happens, don't get too overenthusiastic.
别担心我了  大块头
Don't worry about me, big guy.
我会像蛋一样淡定
I will be cool with a capital "K."
不要秀你的文采
And don't do any spelling.
明白
Check.
请坐吧  伙计们
Have a seat, fellas.
坐这些椅子吗
In these chairs?
得了吧
Forget it.
垃圾堆里捡的吧
They're pieces of junk.
我们不是来买椅子的
We're not buying the chairs.
当然不是了
Darn right we're not.
这一点儿也不好玩
It's not even that fun.
那么  你考虑的怎么样了  鲍伯
So, what do you think, Bob?
想把小夜曲今天就开回家吗
Will you be driving home in a Serenade today?
这个嘛  呃
Well, uh..
我也不确定  斯图  我觉着吧  这一切全看你的了
I don't know, Stu. I guess it, uh, depends on what you can do for me.
没错  斯图  看你的了
Yeah, Stu. What have you got?
开个价吧
Bring it.
这个价钱你满意吗
Does this price work for you?
这个  你满意吗
Does.. This work for you?
喔  喔  喔  PJ  PJ
Whoa, whoa, whoa. PJ, PJ?
我们要先看完价钱再说
We actually have to look at the offers.
菜鸟才这么做  但是随便你啦
Amateur move, but go ahead.
你看啊  鲍伯
Look, Bob.
我想让你满意
I want to make you happy.
这个价钱你满意吗
What do you think about this?
这就是你开的价吗
This is your offer?
PJ
PJ..
你就这点能耐吗  斯图
This is your beef, Stu?
听明白了吗  “红烩牛肉”
Get it? "Beef Stu"?
（注：Beefstew音似Beef Stu）
-听到了  我们  我们都听懂了  -好的
-Yeah, we.. We all got it. -Yeah.
走吧  老爸  我们离开这里
Come on, Dad. We are out of here.
老爸  你来吗
Dad? You coming?
我  呃
I, uh..
我今天选错孩子来陪我买车了  斯图
Chose the wrong child to come with me today, Stu.
我  我道歉
I.. I apologize.
我们玩多长时间了
How long have we been playing?
六个小时
Six hours.
我眼睛都疼了
My eyes are burning.
你应该多眨眨眼
You should blink once in a while.
那不正中了他们的下怀吗
That's exactly what they want.
你是哪边的  扎提亚国王的吗
Who are you working for, the Zartian King?
放松  老兄
Easy, dude.
你电话又响了
Your phone's ringing again.
肯定是我老妈不知道我在哪呢
It's just my Mom wondering where I am.
转到语音信箱吧
Off to voice mail.
我准备走这条小路去检查下变种人
I'm gonna go down this alley and check for mutants.
掩护我
Cover me.
你玩得高兴不  盖比
You having fun, Gabe?
喔
Whoa.
你看见了吗
Did you see that?
什么
What?
我爸  他在游戏里  跟我说话
My Dad. He was.. He was in the game and he was talking to me.
正常
That's normal.
玩六个小时  你会出现幻觉的
After six hours, you're gonna hallucinate.
真的
Really?
是啊  包装盒上写着呢
Yeah. It was a warning on the box.
你只要熬过去就好了
You've just got to power through it.
好吧
Okay.
没错  只要集中注意力
You're right. Just got to focus.
我们要杀掉那个九级的怪兽
We got to get that level nine monster.
这可是你妹妹的生日
It's your baby sister's birthday.
她只想要个娃娃
All she wanted was a doll.
也许你才是怪兽
Maybe you're the monster.
啊
Ah!
你干嘛
What are you doing?
不玩了
We're done.
明天我们把游戏退回去  然后给查莉买娃娃
And tomorrow we're taking the game back and getting Charlie her doll.
你的手怎么回事
What's wrong with your hands?
我也不知道
I don't know.
救救我
Help me.
噢  一周岁生日快乐  你个小可爱
Oh, happy first birthday, you adorable baby.
看看这微笑
Look at that smile.
看看这脸蛋儿
Check out those cheeks.
真想一口吃了
I could just eat you up.
你是最可爱的宝宝了
You are the cutest baby ever.
没错  就是你
Yes, you are.
今天也是我的生日
It's my birthday, too.
噢  爸爸爱你
Oh, and Daddy loves you.
没错  爸爸爱爱你
That's right, Daddy lu-lu you.
伤心了
I'm sad.
噢  我的小可爱
Oh, my little angel.
我不会忘记你的
I could never forget you.
我也不会忘记你的  亲爱的
I'll never forget you either, baby.
不是你
Not you.
泰迪
Teddy.
早啊  妈
Morning, Mom.
泰迪  我今天不能生孩子
Teddy, I can't have this baby today.
查莉需要一个特别的生日
Charlie needs to have her special birthday.
我一直都这么说的啊
That's what I've been saying all along.
是啊  但现在是我说的
Yeah, but now I'm saying it.
好吧  是什么让你改变主意的
Okay, well, what made you change your mind?
我昨晚做了个恐怖的梦
I had this horrible dream last night.
咱们全家人都对查莉很刻薄
The entire family was just being so mean to Charlie..
无视她
Ignoring her.
甚至是你
Even you.
你在你的梦里如何啊
What were you doing in the dream?
我和平常一样啊
I was doing what I always do.
勇于搏斗  让世界更美好
Fighting bravely to make things right.
好了  听着  重点是我今天不能生孩子
Okay, look, the point is I can't have the baby today.
查莉需要属于她的特殊一天
Charlie needs her special day.
好吧  不管你是怎么想的  我绝对同意
All right, well, however you got here, I totally agree.
我们只要保证明天之前不让你分娩就可以了
We'll just make sure that you don't have the baby until tomorrow.
没错  好的
Exactly. Okay.
好的  生宝宝行动
Okay, operation get baby out.
已经正式更改为保胎行动了
Has officially become operation keep baby in.
我需要充足的休息和放松  明白吗
I need complete rest and relaxation, okay?
我只需要平静
Nothing but peace..
冷静
Calm.
和安静
And quiet.
早啊  亲爱的
Morning, honey.
你给我闭嘴
I said quiet!
好吧  又到人间天堂
Yeah. Another day in paradise.
下一个
Next.
嗨  我们想退掉这个游戏
Hi, we'd like to return this game, please.
开封了吗
Has it been opened?
没有
Nope.
那为什么用胶带缠住  而且上面还有牙印
Then why is it covered in tape and what appears to be teeth marks?
好吧
Okay.
我跟你说实话吧
I'm gonna level with you.
我们买这游戏就是个意外
We bought this game by accident.
然后呢  这位杰克
And then, Jake here..
又意外地打开了它
Accidentally opened it.
最后我们又意外地玩了六个小时
And then we accidentally played it for six hours.
伙计们  抱歉了  这个不能退了
Guys, I'm sorry, you can't return this.
噢  不是的  我们没想退货
Oh, no, we don't want to return it.
我们只想用它来换些
We want to exchange it..
钱
For money.
下一位
Next.
噢  这下完了
Oh, this is bad.
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
只能这么办了
Only thing you can do.
偷娃娃
You gotta steal the doll.
偷娃娃  这可是大错特错
Steal the doll? But that's wrong.
此话不假  你知道古人云  “错错得对”
Well, exactly. You know the old saying, "two wrongs make a right."
不是这么说的  应该是“错上加错”
No, it's "two wrongs don't make a right."
噢
Oh.
好吧  那你肯定听说过另外一句
Well, then, you know the other old saying..
“偷娃娃乃人之常情”
"Sometimes you gotta steal a doll."
我不会去偷娃娃的
I'm not gonna steal the doll.
好吧  那至少能偷点儿糖吗
Well, can we at least steal candy?
不
No.
那我们来商店的目的为何
Then what's the point of even going to the store?
小夜曲
Serenade!
耶
Yeah.
噢
Oh.
好了
Well..
希望你从这次的买车之行学到些经验
Hope you learned something from the whole car-buying experience.
那是当然了  老爸
Sure did, Dad.
学到什么了  儿子
What's that, son?
能不能就说到“那是当然了  老爸”而止
Can't we just leave it at a "sure did, Dad"?
我说的是谈判经验
I'm talking about the negotiation.
听着
Look..
将来你也会有自己的家庭
Someday you're gonna have a family of your own.
你也会去买车的
And you're gonna have to buy a new car.
你知道该对你的孩子说什么吗
And you know what you're gonna say to your kid?
车太大了  车库装不下
The car doesn't fit in the garage?
什么
What?
然后我会说“这不是我的错  儿子”
Then I'll say, "it's not my fault, son."
“我全是从你爷爷那里学的”
I learned all this from your grandpa Bob."
然后他会说“噢  怪不得”
And he'll say, "oh, that explains it."
然后我们会开怀大笑  一起去买冰激淋
Then we'll laugh and get ice cream.
怎么了  是你刚才问的
Well, you asked.
然后大家都对你很恶毒
Then everybody was being really mean to you.
但是不要担心  唯独我还是和以往一样宠爱你
But don't you worry, I did what I always do.
勇于搏斗  让世界更美好
Fought bravely to make things right.
查莉  你有这个世界上最好的妈妈
Charlie, you have the best Mommy in the world.
即使在梦里
Even in a dream.
查莉
Charlie?
我给你做了独特的生日午餐
I made you a special birthday lunch.
就在厨房里
It's in the kitchen.
快去吧
Let's go get it.
耶
Yay.
好了  妈
Okay, um, Mom..
我还是有些担心查莉的生日派对
I was just wondering about Charlie's birthday party.
噢   宝贝
Oh, honey.
我需要休息
I have to rest.
你能帮我照顾一下吗
Would you please take care of that for me?
好的  包我身上
Yeah, I got it.
所有你想知道的事情  都在厨房的一个文件夹里
Everything you need to know is in a file in the kitchen.
明白
Got it.
泰迪  你一直这么支持我  我真的
Teddy, you have really been there for me, and I just..
我真的很感激  而且
I'm just so thankful, and..
你是我的依靠
You're my rock.
我不知道没了你该怎么办
I don't know what I'd do without you.
好了
Yeah.
荷尔蒙在作怪吧  老妈
How are the hormones, Mom?
井喷了
All over the place.
查莉  那个小马形状的三明治怎么样啊
Charlie, how'd you like your special pony-shaped sandwich?
好吧  好吧
All right. Well.
亏我花了一个小时来切出形状
Glad I spent an hour cutting it out.
派对文件夹
Party folder.
嘿  查莉  跟我来
Hey, Charlie, come with me.
好了吗  噢  我抱住你了
Ready? Oh! I got 'cha.
好了
Okay.
什么
What?
老妈忘了寄邀请函了
Mom forgot to mail the invitations?
你知道这意味着什么吗
Do you know what this means?
不知道
No.
很好
Good.
你在这儿等着  我马上回来
You wait here. I'll be right back.
爸  嗨  听着
Dad, hi. Okay.
出大事了  你知道老妈因为怀孕而变得有点儿老年痴呆吧
Big problem.. So you know how Mom's been kinda spacey with the pregnancy?
这下好了  她忘了筹备查莉的生日派对了
Well, she forgot to plan Charlie's birthday party.
你以为就你有问题了吗
You think you got problems?
车库短了三十一英寸
The garage is 31 inches too short.
噢  车库太短了
Oh, the garage is too short?
现在成了车库的错了
Now it's the garage's fault?
好吧  买车专家居然没有测量
Yeah, car-buying expert here didn't measure the..
她没必要知道那么多细节
She doesn't need to know the details.
她还有自己的麻烦呢
She has her own situation.
没听刚才说的吗  你妈犯了个又傻又大的错误
Didn't you hear? Mom made a big, dumb mistake.
那  那我该怎么办
Well, so what.. What am I gonna do?
查莉还等着她的派对呢
Charlie's in there waiting for her party.
好吧  好了  给我  呃
Okay, all right. Give me, uh..
给我点儿时间想想
Give me a minute to think.
呃  叭  叭  叭  叭
Uh, bu.. Bu. Bu.. Ba..
有了
Okay..
再多给我点儿时间
Give me another minute.
我
Well, I..
也许我可以给查莉的一些朋友打电话
I guess I could try calling some of Charlie's friends.
看看他们是不是能过来
See if they can come over.
在商店买个蛋糕
Pick up a cake at the store..
在你买蛋糕之前
Before you buy the cake..
你最好量一下冰箱的尺寸
You might wanna measure the fridge.
明白我的意思吗  老爸
Know what I'm saying, Dad?
嗨  呃  迪克逊夫人吗  我是泰迪·邓肯啊
Hi uh, Mrs. Dickson, it's Teddy Duncan calling.
说个事  我在给查莉办一个
Listen, so I'm throwing together
死马当活马医派对
a little last-minute birthday party for Charlie,
我想让梅根过来参加啊
and I was just wondering if Megan could come.
噢  出水痘了
Oh. Chicken pox.
好可怜啊
Poor little thing.
但是  她不用呆很长时间的
But, you know, she doesn't have to stay for long.
好吧
Okay.
好了  我理解
Okay, I understand.
噢  说到这儿
Oh, you know what?
既然正和你聊着呢
As long as I've got you..
请问迪克逊先生能不能
Is there any chance that Mr. Dickson is a..
扮演下小丑或者魔术师啥的
Is a clown or a magician, or..
喂
Hello?
嗨  呃  是蛋糕世界吗
Hi um, is this Cake World?
对  对  嗨
Yeah, yeah, hi.
我要订个蛋糕  呃
I need a cake. Um..
蛋糕卖完了
You're out of cake?
你知道你们叫“蛋糕世界”吗
You realize you're called "Cake World."
也就是说  现在  你们只剩“世界”了
Which means, right now, you're just "world."
怎么了  我也不喜欢你的态度
Yeah, well, I don't like your attitude, either.
喂
Hello?
嗨  呃  嗨  是“艾尔惊奇动物商店”吗
Hi, uh.. Hi, is this "Al's Amazing Animals"?
好的  呃  听着  我知道有点儿仓促
Yeah um, listen, I know that it's last minute,
但是我正在搞一个派对
but I'm trying to put together this birthday party.
你们那里还有什么能让人惊奇的动物吗
What's the most amazing animal you've got?
给吃蛋糕才表演的猴子
A monkey who does tricks for cake.
好吧  有个问题
Yeah, we're gonna have a problem.
呃  有没有可能
Um, by any chance..
可以让猴子自带蛋糕过来
Does the monkey come with its own cake?
喂
Hello?
有谁来我的派对
Who's coming to my party?
跟你说吧  我也不知道
You know, I'm really not sure.
嘿  你知道谁希望来你的派对吗
Hey, you know who might be fun to have at your party?
谁
Who?
操场上的孩子
The kids from the playground.
耶
Yay!
什么孩子
What kids?
这个嘛  到那里见分晓
Well, we won't know until we get there.
耶
Yay!
好了  我到头儿了
Okay, that's as far as I can go.
她怎么样了
How's she looking?
女的吗
It's a she?
你怎么知道的
How can you tell?
你能按下按钮吗
Could you just press the button?
好吧  我这就去
All right, here it goes.
还好
Looking good.
差一点儿
So close.
PJ说的没错
PJ was right.
块儿的没有条儿的有乐趣
The squares aren't as much fun as the sticks.
我还是再来点儿吧
But I'm gonna eat some more anyway.
现在  你该怎么办
So, what are you gonna do?
我能怎么办  和我爸说实话呗
Well, what choice do I have? I have to tell my Dad the truth.
实话  老兄  你玩游戏玩傻了吧
The truth? Dude, that game messed you up.
知道吗  如果你和我一起进去  共背罪名
You know, if you came in and shared some of the blame,
他们还有可能从轻发落我
they'd probably go easier on me.
还是把悬念留下去吧
Guess we'll never know.
不得不承认
Gotta admit..
我欣赏这孩子的做事风格
I like that kid's style.
好了  你  你给我老实的呆着
Okay, you. You stay right where you are.
再来点儿  停
Little more. Stop!
再来点儿
Little more.
停
Stop!
再来点儿
Little more.
停
Stop!
好的
Okay.
快好了
We're getting there.
没有  这个好不了
No, we're not!
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
爸  冷静
Dad, calm down.
不  够了  够了
No, that's it! That's it!
我烦了  烦了
I'm done. Done!
把这大家伙开回经销商那里
Taking this tank back to the.. Dealer!
经销商在那个方向
Dealer's that way.
噢  噢
Oh! Oh!
从这边看  也惨不忍睹
It looks bad from this side, too.
爸  我跟你说
Dad, I have to tell you some..
待会吧
It can wait.
嘿  老爸
Hey, Dad.
好消息啊
Great news.
车库门能关上了
Garage door closes.
同志们  查莉的派对
Guys, Charlie's birthday party is..
不是我们最严重的问题
Not our biggest problem.
你怎么一直喊“欧欧”
Why do you keep saying, "uh-oh"?
你觉着呢
Why do you think?
要生了
The baby's coming.
-噢  -好了  明白了
-Oh! -Okay, all right.
我们要送你妈上医院
We gotta get Mom to the hospital.
来  亲爱的  赶快上车
Come on, honey. Get in the car.
车在墙里呢  老鲍
Car's in the wall, Bob.
来吧  我来开车  艾德在门外呢
Come on, I'll drive. Ed's out front.
艾德  艾德是谁
Ed? Who's Ed?
我的车的名字
That's the name of my car.
艾德  谁的小名  艾德华
Ed? So is that short for uh, Edward?
埃德加  爱德温
Edgar? Edwin?
-艾德  艾德  -救人要紧  PJ
-Ed.. Ed.. -Bigger issues, PJ!
好了  我们必须要走了
Okay, we really need to go.
好的  来吧
Okay, come on.
你们要给查莉办好生日派对
You guys have to throw Charlie her birthday party.
我来开车送老妈上医院
I'm gonna drive Mom to the hospital.
噢  为什么总把艰巨的任务交给我们
Oh, why do we always get the hard things?
知道吗
You know..
我总以为你是第一个把车开进厨房的人
I always thought you would be the first one to drive a car into the kitchen.
我也是
Me, too.
嘿  感觉怎么样了  亲爱的
Hey, how you doing, honey?
如果你能闭嘴就更好了
It'd be a lot better if you were quiet!
她想让我闭嘴
She wants me to be quiet.
我要闭嘴  我怎么就闭不上嘴
Gotta be quiet. Why can't I be quiet?
爸  当初我们出生的时候你也这么慌吗
Dad, were you this panicky when the rest of us were born?
呃 不是
Uh.. No.
因为前四次  我们都是提前进医院生的
Because the first four times we did this, we were at a hospital!
我们生的  说得真好
We did this, yeah.
你给我生一次试试
Yeah, you wanna take over?!
好了  大家请冷静
Okay, everybody relax.
我们正往那里赶呢  我们能尽快赶到的
We're on our way. We're gonna be there shortly.
先处理一下这个  小问题
Right after this.. Slight delay.
没油了
You're outta gas.
车没油了  泰迪
You're outta gas! Aw, Teddy.
你怎么能这么不靠谱
How could you be so irresponsible?!
你可是把车开进厨房的人
Says the guy who drove a car into our kitchen.
闭上眼睛  没错
Close your eyes. There you go.
好了
Okay.
准备
Ready?
别睁开
Keep 'em closed.
好的  准备  生日快乐
Okay. And.. Surprise!
嘿
Hey!
看看都谁来参加你的派对了
Look who came to your party, Charlie.
三个最熟识最要好的朋友
Three of your oldest and bestest friends.
网球头
Tennis ball head.
恐怖小丑
Scary clown.
啊
Ah!
还有
And..
残疾猴
Badly-damaged monkey.
我  我觉着她不喜欢这些
I.. I don't think she likes it.
这个  她  她会喜欢的
Well, she's.. She's about to.
-噢  好的  -因为
-Oh, okay. -Because..
看啊
Ta-da!
生日快乐
Happy Birthday!
这是你的特别生日蛋糕
It's your special birthday cake.
这不是蛋糕
That's not cake.
是特别生日百吉饼
It's your special birthday bagel.
恩  百吉饼  网球头的最爱
Mm, bagel. Tennis ball head's. Favorite.
我的礼物呢
Where's my present?
是啊  你买到凯蒂洋娃娃了吗
Yeah, did you get the Kuddle Me Katie doll?
你搞毛啊  这又不是访谈节目  享受下派对不成吗
What is this, "60 minutes"? Just enjoy the party.
查莉  我们弄了一些有趣的生日派对游戏
Charlie.. We have got some really fun party games planned.
比如
Like..
看电视
Watching TV!
耶
Yay!
我想看公主
I want princesses.
是吗
Really?
呃  妈咪批准你看公主了吗
Uh, did Mommy promise you a Princess?
妈咪说  “两位公主”
Mommy said, "two princesses, please."
好吧  你听到她说的了  公主
All right, you heard her, Princess.
快去实现吧
Make it happen.
妈咪说要两位公主
Mommy said two.
深呼吸
Just breathe.
我确信老爸会找来车的
I'm sure Dad will find us a ride soon.
是吗  难道因为他对车很在行吗
Yeah, because he's so good with cars?
嘿  抱歉久等了
Hey, sorry it took so long.
这个时候你还买冰淇淋
You went for ice cream at a time like this?
呃  这个嘛
Uh, well..
事实是  冰淇淋找到的我
Actually, the ice cream came to me.
你用冰淇淋车送我去医院
You're taking me to the hospital in an ice cream truck?
你说让我看见什么车就截什么车
You said to flag down the first thing I saw.
噢  出问题了吗  难道热狗车不停吗
Oh what's the matter, the giant hot dog wouldn't stop?
是啊
Yeah.
别说了
Okay.
推  泰迪
Push, Teddy.
欢迎登陆大胡子皮特号  坐冰淇淋车吃开心果
Welcome aboard Mustachio Pete's, the ice cream truck with the pistachio treats.
提醒一下  开心果已经停止供应了
FYI, pistachio has been discontinued.
老鲍  我需要躺下
Bob, I need to lie down.
-好的  -你可以躺在豆袋椅上
-Okay. -You can use that bean bag chair.
那就是大胡子皮特小憩时候用的
It's where Mustachio Pete takes his 10 minute breaks..
大胡子皮特是按照规定才休息的
Which Mustachio Pete is allowed by law.
你不会一直用第三人称来提到自己吧
You're not gonna keep referring to yourself in the third person, are you?
会的  他会的
Yes, he is.
这就是大胡子皮特的特点
That's Mustachio Pete's trademark.
还有开心果  提醒一下
That, and the pistachio, which, FYI..
已经停止供应了
Has been discontinued.
我们知道了  好了  进来吧  亲爱的
We get.. We.. Okay. Come on, honey.
如果痛得难受了  就咬一下火箭
If things get bad back there, bite down on a rocket pop.
噢  好的  我会的
Ooh, cool, I will.
他说的是我
He meant me!
能走了吗  情况很紧急的
Can we get going? It's an emergency.
紧急
Emergency?
那我要配上极速音乐了
This calls for the fast-paced music.
准备好了吗  查莉
Ready, Charlie?
公主时间到
It's Princess time!
我好像弄丢了我的公主妹妹
I seem to have lost my sister Princess.
请稍等
Excuse me.
-快出来  -我感觉好白痴
-Get out there! -But I feel stupid!
-你以为我不白痴吗  -你已经习惯了
-You think I don't? -You're used to it!
出去
Go!
跳舞啊  公主
Dance, Princess.
左边  再右边
Left.. And right.
施个咒
And we cast a spell.
转啊  转啊
And we twirl and we twirl.
行屈膝礼
And we curtsy!
看看笑的多开心
Look at that smile.
我们要再跳一边
We gotta go again.
什么
What?
但是  这次  跟上我的节奏
But, this time, stay with me.
五  六  七  八
And five, six, seven, eight.
左  右
Left, right..
你能再开快点儿吗
Can't you go any faster?
已经二十三迈了
We're already doing 23.
已经是极速了
I'm giving her all she's got.
好吧
Okay.
快生了  还有多远
Baby's close. How much further?
你是不是吃了后面的免费赠品啊  鲍伯
You're not helping yourself to any freebies back there, are you, Bob?
我一有压力就要吃  皮特
I'm a stress eater, Pete.
你不用跟我讲压力
You don't have to tell me about stress.
冰淇淋业就是弱肉强食啊
The ice cream truck business is dog-eat-dog.
鬓角山姆一直抢我的生意
I got Side Burn Sam nipping at my heels.
我们能把注意力放在路上吗  皮特
Could we just focus on the road, Pete?
但是这两位公主都太漂亮了
But both princesses are so beautiful.
我怎能从中选一位成为我的妻子呢
How could I ever choose just one to be my wife?
老弟  该你了
Dude, that's your line.
噢  对
Oh, right.
这个嘛  我猜只有一个办法了
Well, I guess there's only one way.
看看谁能穿进魔法水晶拖鞋
See whose foot fits the magic slipper.
好的
Okay.
看来我穿不进去这只拖鞋
'Tis not I whose foot doth fit the slipper.
是的  我也穿不进去
Yes, 'tis not me, either.
但是  公主小妹  你还没试呢
But, sister Princess, you have not tried on the slipper.
我不想试
I doth not want to.
噢  你会的
Oh, yeth you will.
不然我就要揍你了
Or I will hurteth you.
用我的拳头
With my fitht.
噢  好开心啊
Oh, joy.
穿进去了
It fits.
娘子
My bride!
我可算寻到你了
At long last I have found you.
然后他们献上了定情之吻
And they seal their love.. With a kiss.
好了  演完了
Okay, we're done!
没有  还没完
Yeah, not quite.
我们再从头来一遍
We're gonna go again from the top.
也许你这次能演对了
Maybe you'll get it right this time.
啊
Ah!
嘿
Hey..
我需要你来后面帮忙
I'm gonna need your help back here.
老爸  我不会接生啊
Dad, I don't know how to deliver a baby.
宝贝  你要帮帮我啊
Honey, you just gotta help me.
留我一个人在后面  我说说而已
All alone back here! Just sayin'.
好吧
Okay.
-你还好吧  老妈  -嘿
-How you doing, Mom? -Hey.
孩子马上就要出来了
This baby is coming now.
那就
Then..
来迎接宝宝吧
Let's have a baby.
好了  泰迪
Okay, Teddy.
开始吧
Here we go.
噢  哇
Oh, wow.
你好啊  邓肯五号
Well, hello, number five.
多么可爱的小男孩啊
What a beautiful baby boy.
是不是很可爱
Isn't he precious?
我们以最快速度赶到了
We got here as fast as we could.
嗨
Hi.
小寿星来了
There's the birthday girl.
生日快乐
Happy Birthday.
查莉  过来
Charlie, come here.
见见你的小弟弟
Meet your new baby brother.
小弟弟
Brother?
酷
Cool.
嘿  取名字了吗
Hey, what name did you pick?
取了  我们决定叫他
Well, we decided to call him..
托比
Toby.
嘿
Hey.
是我以前提出来的  漂亮
I came up with that one. Nice.
欢迎来到这个世界上  托比·邓肯
Welcome to the world, Toby Duncan.
嘿  问个问题
Hey, quick question.
你们俩怎么穿成这样
Why are you guys dressed like that?
噢  因为
Oh, because..
老妈答应查莉在派对上要有公主
Mom promised Charlie princesses for her party.
我没有答应过查莉啊
I never promised Charlie princesses.
查莉  你耍我们吗
Charlie, did you trick us?
宝贝  你拿到了你的特殊生日礼物  凯蒂洋娃娃了吗
Sweetie, did you get your special birthday present, Kuddle Me Katie?
没有  妈咪
No, Mommy.
什么  为什么
What? Why not?
老鲍
Bob?
盖比
Gabe?
PJ
PJ?
泰迪
Teddy?
盖比
Gabe?
宝贝  真抱歉
Sweetie, I'm sorry.
这个生日不是很满意  对吧
Wasn't much of a birthday, was it?
没事的  妈咪
That's okay, Mommy.
现在  不用担心  我们会送你一个特殊礼物的
Now, don't you worry. We will get you your special present.
我喜欢这个礼物
I like this present.
好了  听好了  计划是这样的
Okay, listen up. Here's the plan.
当他们从前门进来的时候  你们俩
So, when they come through the front door, you guys..
拿着这个横幅
Are gonna hold up this banner.
给  拿着
Here. Take that.
查莉呢  你要送给妈咪这些气球
And Charlie, you're gonna give Mommy these balloons.
我来吹小喇叭
And I'm gonna blow the noisemaker.
然后我们要唱“欢迎回家  托比”
And then we're all gonna sing "welcome home, Toby"
配合那首摇滚经典歌曲  “我们的家”的曲调
To the tune of the rock classic.. "Our House."
为什么你来吹小喇叭
Why do you get to blow the noisemaker?
还有我们为什么总搞得这么隆重
And why are we making such a big deal outta this?
感觉他们平均六个月就会带回来一个孩子
They bring a new baby home like every six months.
这是我们的传统
This is what we always do.
我们也这么迎接过查莉
We did it for Charlie.
迎接我的时候有什么
Did you do it for me?
呃  是啊
Uh.. Yeah.
-你在撒谎  -没有  我没有
-You're lying! -No, I'm not.
是的  你撒谎
Yeah, you are.
你  知道吗  如果你没有为我做这些  我也不为托比做
You.. You know what? If you didn't do it for me, I'm not doing it for Toby.
不管他的名字有多酷
No matter how cool his name is.
盖比  赶紧捡起这白痴横幅
Gabe, just pick up the stupid banner
然后赶紧加入到这感人的家庭庆典中
and join in this very touching family celebration!
你不能强迫我
You can't make me.
好吧  如果他不做  我也不做了
Well, if he's not gonna do it, I'm not gonna do it.
如果我们不一起的话
And if we not all gonna do it together..
感觉查莉可以干这些活儿
... It looks like Charlie could have made it.
到家真好
Good to be home.
就是这样  对不对  现在我明白
This is what it's all about, isn't it? Now I see..
让我带你四处逛逛
So let me show you around.
这就是你的家  托比  是啊
This is your home, Toby. Yeah.
这里是客厅
This is the living room.
这是你的家人
And this is your family.
告诉我谁是你的天使
<i>Tell me who's your angel.</i>
谁的肩膀  为你扛着重担
<i>Who's your shoulder, to hold your boulders.</i>
告诉我下雨时
<i>Tell me when it's raining.</i>
是谁提醒你
<i>Who will warm you.</i>
是谁抱住你
<i>Who will hold you.</i>
你也许会体无完肤
<i>You might be broken.</i>
伤心欲绝
<i>With all these cracks in your skin.</i>
伤心之处  必有光芒照进
<i>You might be broken that's where the light gets in.</i>
你是如此美丽  美丽  美丽
<i>You're something beautiful, beautiful, beautiful.</i>
我只想让你知道  让你知道  让你知道
<i>And I just want you to know. You to know. You to know.</i>
你并不孤独
<i>That you're not alone.</i>
<i>You're not alone.</i>
嘿  你干啥呢
Hey, what you doing?
给托比介绍下咱们家
Giving Toby a proper welcome home.
好了  查莉  这周绝对不平凡
Well, Charlie, it's been kind of a big week.
我  呃  我帮忙接生个宝宝
I uh, I helped deliver a baby..
我们的小弟弟  托比
Our little brother, Toby..
而你最终得到了凯蒂洋娃娃
And you finally got your Kuddle Me Katie.
你五分钟之后就玩腻了
Which you lost interest in five minutes after you got it.
没关系的  盖比还是会付出代价的
Doesn't matter, Gabe's still paying for it.
他已经和老爸老妈协商好了
He worked out a little agreement with Mom and Dad.
盖比  换尿布
Gabe! Diaper change!
这次臭臭的
And it's a doozy.
来了
Coming.
祝他好运吧  查莉
Wish him good luck, Charlie.
好可爱啊
Isn't he adorable?
噢   小托比
Oh, little Toby.
当然了
He sure is.
噢  对了  他的中间名是什么
Oh, by the way, what's his middle name?
旺·肯诺比
Wan-Kenobi.
托比·旺·肯诺比
Toby Wan-Kenobi?
Obi Wan Kenobi：绝地武士
是啊  是啊  你老爸是“星球大战”的忠实影迷
Yeah. Yup, your Dad's a big fan of the movies.
说到你老爸  他在哪呢
Speaking of, where is Dad?
我准备回家了
I'm ready to go home.
他说他去停车了
He said he was just going to pull the car up.
现在他到了
Here he is now.
嘿  准备好了吗
Hey! Ready to go hun?
好了  乖乖  你是怎么办到的
Yes, babe how did you do that?
我们在八层
We're on the eighth floor.
嘿  这宝贝不一般啊
Hey, this baby's got some pick-up.
是啊
Yeah.
小夜曲
Serenade!
PJ·达斯·邓肯
PJ Darth Duncan!
Darth：黑武士
你要吵醒你的小弟弟了
You're going to wake your baby brother.
噢  抱歉
Oh, sorry.
小夜曲
Serenade!